Hey there. How's it going everybody? In
嘿。 大家好吗？ 在
this video, we're going to be learning
本视频中，我们将学习
about UV, which is a new package manager
UV，这是一个新的 Python 包管理器，
for Python that's growing pretty quickly
其受欢迎程度正在迅速增长
in popularity. Now, the goal with UV is
。 现在，利用紫外线照射的目标
pretty ambitious. They want it to be a
相当远大。 他们希望它成为一个
single tool that can replace pip for
可以替代 pip（用于
installing packages, venv or virtual env
安装软件包）、venv（虚拟环境）或 virtual env（
for creating and managing virtual
用于创建和管理虚拟
environments. Uh, pip tools for
环境）的单一工具。 嗯，pip 工具用于
generating lock files, and even pip x
生成锁定文件，甚至还有 pip x
for installing and running Python tools.
用于安装和运行 Python 工具。
UV combines all of these tools into one.
UV 将所有这些工具整合到一个工具中。
And also, it's quite a bit faster than
而且，
those other options since it's written
由于它是用 Rust 编写的，所以速度比其他选项快得多
in Rust. It's created and maintained by
。 它由 Astral 创建和维护
Astral, which is the same team behind
，Astral 也是 Roughliner 背后的团队，Roughliner
the Roughliner that's also becoming very
也越来越
popular. And we're going to look at
受欢迎。 我们还将
Rough in an upcoming tutorial as well.
在接下来的教程中学习粗略绘制。
But in this video, we'll compare how a
但在本视频中，我们将比较
UV workflow compares to a standard
UV 工作流程与使用
workflow with PIP and Venv and try to
PIP 和 Venv 的标准工作流程有何不同，并尝试
get a sense of why so many people are
了解为什么这么多人正在
switching over to using this as their
转向使用 UV 工作流程作为
default. So, with that said, let's go
默认工作流程。 那么，话不多说，让我们
ahead and get started. All right, so
开始吧。 好的，
first let's get UV installed on our
首先我们来把紫外线灯安装到我们的
system. There are a few different ways
系统上。 安装这个软件有几种不同的方法
to install this, and I'll show you the
，我会向你展示
one that I'm going to use, but also
我将要使用的方法，同时也会
mention some alternatives. Uh, I'm on a
提到一些其他方法。 呃，我用的是
Mac and I like using Homebrew. So,
Mac电脑，我喜欢用Homebrew。 所以，
that's the method that I'm going to use
这就是我将要使用的方法，
if you already have Homebrew set up, but
如果您已经安装了 Homebrew，这可能是最简单的方法，但
I'm also going to leave a link to this
我也会在下面的描述部分留下一个指向此
installation page in the description
安装页面的链接，
section below so that you can see the
以便您可以查看
other ways that we can install this
我们可以在这里安装它的其他方法
here. So, for example, you can see that
。 例如，您可以看到
they have a standalone installer with uh
他们提供了一个独立的安装程序，
just using a curl command on Mac or uh
只需在 Mac 或 Linux 上使用 curl 命令即可
Linux. On Windows, you can run a
。 在 Windows 系统中，您可以运行
PowerShell command and then they have a
PowerShell 命令，然后
bunch of different options here as well.
这里也有很多不同的选项。
Um, but like I said, I'm going to be
嗯，不过就像我说的，我打算
using the homebrew option. So, let me go
使用自制软件。 好，我
back to my terminal here and I'm going
回到我的终端，我要用
to install this uh using homebrew. And
Homebrew 安装这个。
I'll just say brew install
我只需说 brew install
UV. And once it says that's installed, I
UV 即可。 一旦显示安装完成，我
should be able to test this just by
应该可以通过
running uv. And we can see there that uh
运行 uv 来进行测试。 我们可以看到，这里
we get a list of all the commands that
列出了我们
we can use with this. So that is
可以与此一起使用的所有命令。 已经
installed and it's working. So now that
安装完毕，而且运行正常。 既然
we have UV installed, let's take a look
我们已经安装了紫外线消毒器，那么让我们来看看
at how it's used compared to the
它与
traditional tools that we might be more
我们可能更熟悉的传统工具相比，有哪些使用方法
familiar with. So if I were to start
。 所以，如果我要
working on a new Python project, here's
开始一个新的 Python 项目，
basically what I normally would have
我通常会这样做
done. So I would create a directory for
。 所以我会为
my project. So I'm going to create a
我的项目创建一个目录。 所以我要在这里创建一个
directory here and I'll just call this
目录，我就把它叫做“
old way. and then I will cd into that
旧方法”。 然后我将使用 cd 命令进入该
directory. And then probably one of the
目录。 然后，
first things that you'd want to do is
你首先要做的事情之一可能就是
create a new virtual environment. So I
创建一个新的虚拟环境。 所以我打算使用
would do something like Python 3 and I
Python 3，并且在
would use venv here. I'll just create a
这里使用虚拟环境。 我将创建一个
virtual environment called veenv. Uh now
名为 veenv 的虚拟环境。 呃，
if you've not if you're not familiar
如果你还不
with virtual environments, don't worry
熟悉虚拟环境，也不用担心
about it. I'm just showing you the old
。 我现在只是给你们展示一下旧
way for now and we'll look at the uh UV
方法，我们马上就会看到更
way which is a lot simpler here in just
简单的紫外线方法
a second. So, I'm going to create this
。 所以，我将在这里创建一个
virtual environment here. And then we'd
虚拟环境。 然后我们就
want to activate that virtual
需要激活那个虚拟
environment. So, uh I'm on a Mac, so I
环境。 嗯，我用的是Mac电脑，所以我
would say I would source that. And that
会说我会从Mac电脑上找资源。 它
is going to be in the bin directory.
将会放在 bin 目录下。
Activate. And we can see I have my
激活。 我们可以看到，我的
terminal set up here to show me when I'm
终端已经设置好，可以显示我何时
within a virtual environment. So, we can
处于虚拟环境中。 所以我们可以
see that that is active. And then, uh
看到它是有效的。 然后，
normally we would uh just use pip to
通常情况下，我们会使用 pip 来
install whatever packages that we wanted
安装我们
on this new project. So let's say that I
在这个新项目中需要的任何软件包。 假设我
wanted to use flask and request. So I
想使用 Flask 和 Requests。 所以我
would say pip install flask request and
建议使用 pip 安装 flask request，
then we would go about it that way. And
然后我们再按这个方法进行操作。
we can see that just took a couple of
我们可以看到，这只用了几
seconds there. And then after we had
秒钟时间。 然后，在我们
whatever packages we wanted installed,
安装完所有需要的软件包之后，
then we would create the project
我们将为
structure for this new project. Uh so
这个新项目创建项目结构。 嗯，那
for now, let's just create a simple
现在，我们先创建一个简单的
main. py file. So let me go ahead and
main 函数。  py 文件。 那我先
clear my screen here. I'll just do a uh
清空一下屏幕。 我来做一个简单的
touch main. py which just creates a
主操作。  py 只会创建一个
blank main. py file. And now let me uh
空白的主程序。  py 文件。 现在让我把
list everything off in my directory
我目录里的所有东西都列出来
here. So we can see that we have our
。 所以我们可以看到，
virtual environment here.
这里就是我们的虚拟环境。
Envy file. And after I worked on my
Envy 文件。 在我花了
script here for a bit, I'd likely want
一些时间编写脚本之后，我可能会想要
to create a requirements file so that I
创建一个需求文件，以便我
can reproduce this project and share it
可以重现这个项目并
with other people. Uh so to do that uh
与其他人分享。 呃，所以
using the old way using pip uh I would
要用老方法，用 pip 来做这件事，我会
say pip freeze and then I would redirect
说 pip freeze，然后我会把
this to a uh
它重定向到一个
requirements.txt file. And if we look at
requirements.txt 文件。 如果我们看一下
this file so I will just cat that out.
这个文件，我就把它输出出来。
Then we can see that it lists all of our
然后我们可以看到，
dependencies here of the packages that
这里列出了我们已安装软件包的所有依赖项
we installed. And we only installed
。 我们只安装了
flask and request but both of those uh
flask 和 request，但是这两个软件包
depend on other packages of their own.
本身又依赖于其他软件包。
So that's why we're seeing additional
所以这就是为什么我们在
dependencies listed here. Uh so then if
这里看到列出了额外的依赖项。 呃，所以如果
I pass this off to someone else, then
我把这个项目交给其他人，
they could recreate my project by
他们就可以通过
creating and activating their own
创建和激活自己的
virtual environment and then installing
虚拟环境，然后
the dependencies uh from this
从
requirements.txt file that I have here.
我这里提供的 requirements.txt 文件中安装依赖项来重新创建我的项目。
So that is a lot of steps and it's not
所以步骤很多，而且
especially for newcomers. So now let's
对于新手来说，这个过程并不十分直观。 现在让我们
see how this compares to using UV. So
看看这种方法与使用紫外线相比有何不同。 所以
I'm going to go up one directory here
我要返回上一级目录，
back to my desktop and we can see that
回到我的桌面，我们可以看到
we just have that old way project there.
那里只有那个旧方法项目。
And now let's create a new project using
现在让我们使用 UV 创建一个新项目
UV. So instead of creating a new
。 所以，与其像以前那样从头开始创建一个新
directory from scratch like I did
目录，
before, I can instead let UV do that for
不如让 UV 帮
me just by saying UV and we'll call this
我完成，只需说“UV”，然后我们把这个
new app. So I'll run that, we can see
新应用命名为“UV”。 所以我运行了一下，我们可以看到
that it initialized a project. And now
它初始化了一个项目。 现在，
if I cd into this new application here.
如果我进入这个新应用程序。
And just a quick side note, if you
另外，补充一点，如果您
already had a project directory but
已经有一个项目目录，但
didn't create it using uv, then you
不是用 uv 创建的，那么您
could also cd into that directory and
也可以 cd 到该目录，然后
just run
运行
uvit uh without the directory name and
uvit uh（不带目录名称），
it will set up the directory you're
它会将您
currently using as a new application.
当前使用的目录设置为一个新的应用程序。   我在
to it when I created this, but UV does
创建这个项目时没有添加任何其他选项，但是 UV 在初始化项目时确实提供了
have a few different project types to
几种不同的项目类型供
choose from when initializing a project.
选择。
So first there is the app option and app
首先是应用选项，应用
is the default. So this is what was run
是默认选项。 这就是
when I just created uh my new project
我创建新项目时运行的命令
here. And like I said, this is the
。 正如我所说，这是
default. This is what I use most often.
默认设置。 这是我最常用的。
It creates a simple project structure
它
for applications, scripts, uh web
为应用程序、脚本、Web
servers and things like that. Uh but
服务器等等创建了一个简单的项目结构。 呃，但是
there is also lib and lib creates a
还有 lib，lib 可以创建一个
project that is designed to be built and
旨在构建和
distributed as a Python package. Uh I'd
分发为 Python 包的项目。 嗯，我觉得
say most of us will be using the app
我们大多数人都会使用应用程序的
default. Uh but the option to create
默认设置。 嗯，如果你感兴趣的话，创建
distributable Python packages is there
可分发的 Python 包也是可以的
if you're curious. So let me clear this
。 让我把话说清楚
out. Okay. Okay, so now let's look at
。 好的。 好的，现在让我们来看看
what UV created for us with the default
UV 使用应用程序的默认初始化为我们创建了什么
init for an application. So if I list
。 如果我列出
all the files here, so first we have a
这里所有的文件，首先我们有一个
git directory and a git ignore file. So
git 目录和一个 git 忽略文件。 因此，
UV automatically initializes a git
UV 会自动为我们初始化一个 git
repository for us, which is nice because
仓库，这很好，因为
most of us will want to track our code
我们大多数人
within version control anyway. Uh the
无论如何都希望在版本控制中跟踪我们的代码。
git ignore file has some common uh
git ignore 文件包含一些常见的
python specific files that we typically
Python 特定文件，我们通常
don't want to track in git uh like cache
不希望在 git 中跟踪这些文件，例如缓存
files and the virtual environment.
文件和虚拟环境。
There's also a python version file which
此外，还有一个 python 版本文件，其中
contains the python version this project
包含此项目
is configured to use. UV uses this to
配置使用的 python 版本。  UV 利用这一点来
ensure that we're working with a
确保我们在构建此应用程序时使用的是
consistent Python version as we're
一致的 Python 版本
building this application. Uh right now
。 嗯，
it probably contains the version of
它现在可能包含了
Python that we have installed on our
我们系统上安装的 Python 版本
system. Uh but we can change this if
。 嗯，不过如果需要的话我们可以修改
needed. And then we have a readme file
。 然后我们还有一个
uh which is currently empty. Uh but this
目前为空的 readme 文件。 呃，但
is where you'd typically add
通常情况下，你应该在这里添加
documentation about your project. And
有关项目的文档。
then this main.py file here is a simple
然后，这里的 main.py 文件是
starter Python file for our application.
我们应用程序的一个简单的 Python 起始文件。
Uh UV creates this as a placeholder
Uh UV 会创建一个占位符，
where we can begin writing our code. And
我们可以在这里开始编写代码。
finally we have the pi project.totml
最后，我们还有 pi 项目.totml
file uh which is a modern way to
文件，这是一种
configure Python projects. So let's take
配置 Python 项目的现代方法。 那么我们
a quick look at that. Uh I'm just going
快速看一下。 呃，我这就直接在
project within VS Code. Okay. And now
VS Code 中打开整个项目。 好的。 现在
let me open up that pi project.l file
让我打开之前看到的 pi project.l 文件
that we saw before. So this has some
。 这里包含一些
basic information about our application.
关于我们应用程序的基本信息。
And at the bottom we can see it's
在底部我们可以看到它
listing our dependencies. Right now it's
列出了我们的依赖项。 目前这是
an empty list because we haven't added
一个空列表，因为我们还没有添加
any packages uh that we're going to use
任何要用
for this application yet. Now, this is
于此应用程序的软件包。 通常情况下，
normally where we'd create and activate
我们会在这里创建并激活
our virtual environment, but we don't
虚拟环境，但在这里我们不需
need to do that here. Uh, UV will handle
要这样做。 嗯，UV 会在我们
that for us automatically the first time
第一次
that we run a command that actually
运行真正
needs it. Uh, so let's add those
需要它的命令时自动为我们处理它。 嗯，那么让我们添加
packages in uh that we used in our last
我们在上一个例子中使用的那些包
example. So, I'm going to go back to the
。 所以，我要回到
terminal here. So, now I'm going to
航站楼了。 现在我要像
before, but instead of pip, I'm going to
以前一样安装 flash 和 request，但是这次我不使用 pip，而是
use uv. So I'll say uv add flask and
使用 uv。 所以我会说添加紫外线烧瓶并
request. And if I run that then we can
提出请求。 如果我运行这段代码，我们就可以
see that finishes up. It was a bit
看到它最终完成了。
quicker than the pip installation was.
比使用pip安装要快一些。
And also if I look towards the top here
此外，如果我看一下顶部，
we can see that it tells us the Python
我们可以看到它告诉我们它
interpreter that it's using and also
正在使用的 Python 解释器，并且还
detected that we need a virtual
检测到我们需要一个虚拟
environment. So it created this.v VNV
环境。 所以它在这里为我们的项目创建了 this.v VNV
directory here uh right here for us in
目录，
our project and then it installs flask
然后它
and request into that environment and
在该环境中安装了 flask 和 request，
there are a couple other things that it
它还做了其他一些事情
did here as well. Uh if I open that
。 嗯，如果我重新打开那个
project back up then we can see that it
项目，我们可以看到它
also updated our piprototl file here to
也更新了这里的 piprototl 文件，将
list flask and request as dependencies.
flask 和 request 列为依赖项。   还有一
Uh another thing is that it created this
件事，它为我们创建了这个
uv.lock file for us. So let me open this
uv.lock 文件。 那么，让我来打开它
up. And this lock file records the exact
。 该锁定文件记录了
versions of all the packages installed
所有已安装软件包（
including subd dependencies. Uh so this
包括 subd 依赖项）的确切版本。 这样可以
ensures that your environment is
确保您的环境
perfectly reproducible and it does all
完全可复现，而且这一切都
of that without us creating or
无需我们创建或
activating any virtual environments. So
激活任何虚拟环境。 所以，
basically it helps to uh prevent the
它基本上有助于防止
because of some small discrepancy
因某些细微差异而导致的经典问题，即程序在一台机器上运行正常，但在另一台机器上却无法运行
somewhere. And UV also has this uh nice
。  UV还有一个很棒的
feature here for visualizing and
功能，可以用来可视化和
understanding our dependencies. So if I
理解我们的依赖关系。 所以，如果我
wanted to see a tree of my dependencies
想查看我的依赖关系树，
to see what relies on what, then I could
看看哪些依赖关系，那么我只需
just run UV tree here within my project.
在我的项目中运行 UV tree 即可。
And we can see that our two main ones
我们可以看到，这里主要有两个框架
here are Flask and request. And within
是 Flask 和 request。 在
Flask, these are the subd dependencies
Flask 中，这些是这里的子依赖项
here. And with request, these are the
。 如有需要，以下是
subd dependencies here. Okay. So now
这里的子依赖项。 好的。 假设
let's say that we work on our
我们已经开发了
application for a while and now we want
一段时间的应用程序，现在我们想要
to run it. How would we do that from the
运行它。
command line if that virtual environment
如果虚拟环境
isn't activated? So from an IDE, this
没有激活，我们如何通过命令行实现这一点？ 所以从集成开发环境（IDE）来看，这
should be fairly simple. Uh for example,
应该相当简单。 例如，
let me open up that main.py file here
让我用 VS Code 打开这个 main.py 文件
within VS Code. So I'll open this up. So
。 那我打开看看。 因此，
within most IDE, you should have an easy
在大多数 IDE 中，您应该可以轻松地在
your current project. Mine automatically
当前项目中查找虚拟环境。 我的程序会自动
selects virtual environments inside of
选择项目中存在的虚拟环境
my projects if they exist. Uh, but we
。 呃，但
actually open this project before that
实际上，我们是在创建该环境之前就启动了这个项目
environment was created. So to select
。 所以要选中
it, I just have to navigate down here to
它，我只需要向下滚动到
the bottom right. And we can see that
右下角。 我们可以看到
it's using this uh
它在
3.13 here. And I'm just going to have it
这里使用的是 3.13 版本。 我打算让它
select this virtual environment here
选择我目录下的这个虚拟环境
within my directory. And just to make
。 为了
sure that this works, uh, let's print
确保一切正常，我们来打印
out the Python executable that's
出正在
executing our script. Uh, that way we
执行我们脚本的 Python 可执行文件。 嗯，这样我们
can be sure that it's using the correct
就能确保它使用的是正确的
environment. So to do this, I'll just
环境。 所以，要做到这一点，我只需要
import CIS. And then where we are
导入CIS即可。 然后，在我们
printing out here, I will print out uh
打印输出的地方，我将打印出
CIS.executable. So now if I save this
CIS.executable。 所以现在如果我保存
and run it within VS code, then we can
并在 VS Code 中运行它，那么我们可以
see here that it is using that correct
看到它正在使用正确的
uh Python virtual environment. So, we're
Python 虚拟环境。 所以，我们现在
within our new app and our virtual
身处我们的新应用程序和虚拟
environment here. So, we're able to run
环境中。 因此，我们可以
this easily from an IDE. But now, let's
轻松地从集成开发环境 (IDE) 中运行它。 但现在，让我们
go back to our terminal and see how we
回到终端，看看如何
would run it from there. So, let me
从那里运行它。 让我先
clear out my terminal here. And
清空一下终端。
actually, I never deactivated this
事实上，我之前从未停用过这个
virtual environment from before. Uh,
虚拟环境。 还好
glad that didn't screw anything up. Let
没出什么岔子。
me go ahead and deactivate that really
我这就
quick. Okay. So, now with UV, we're not
快速把它停用。 好的。 所以，现在有了紫外线，我们就不再
in that same paradigm of having our
处于那种
environment active at all times.
环境始终处于活跃状态的模式了。
Instead, we're going to let UV handle
相反，我们将让紫外线来处理
that for us. So, instead of doing
这件事。 所以，与其做类似“
something like uh Python main. py, uh
呃，Python main”这样的事情。  py，呃，
we're going to instead say uv run main.
我们改用 uv run main。
py. And if I run this, then we can see
py。 如果我运行这个命令，我们就可以看到
environments active right now. Uh but uv
目前没有任何活跃的虚拟环境。 但是 uv
runs the code and automatically uses
运行代码后会自动使用
that virtual environment that it created
它之前创建的虚拟环境
earlier. Uh but now let me show you
。 呃，不过现在让我给你展示一些
something that's pretty impressive. So
非常了不起的东西。
let's say that the virtual environment
假设虚拟环境
gets removed or deleted. So I'll go
被移除或删除。 所以我打算把它
from my project. So I will uh
从我的项目中彻底删除。 所以我会
say remove that virtual environment. And
说，移除那个虚拟环境。
now we can see that there is no virtual
现在我们可以看出，这里并不存在虚拟
environment here. And normally this
环境。 通常情况下，这
would screw us up. Uh we'd have to go in
会给我们带来麻烦。 呃，我们得
and create this environment again.
重新创造这个环境。
activate it and then install the
激活它，然后安装
packages to run our code and then
运行我们代码所需的软件包，
finally be able to run our code. But all
最后才能运行我们的代码。 但是，
of the information that we need to run
运行
this code is in our PI project and lock
这段代码所需的所有信息都在我们的 PI 项目和锁定
files. So with UV, if I just try to run
文件中。 所以，如果我使用 UV
this again with UV run main. py, if I
再次运行这个程序，运行主程序。 如果我
run this, then we can see that it runs
运行这段代码，我们可以看到它运行得
that just fine. And what it did was it
很好。 它
saw that we didn't have a virtual
发现我们没有虚拟
environment. So it created that for us.
环境。 所以它为我们创造了这一切。
Then it installed all of those packages
然后它很快就安装了所有这些软件包
very quickly. And then it ran the code
。 然后它
for us, all with one command. And not
用一条命令就为我们运行了代码。
only that, but it was extremely fast as
不仅如此，它的速度也极快
well. Much faster than if we'd done this
。 比
with pip and VNV. And we don't even need
用 pip 和 VNV 快得多。 我们甚至不需要
to run that main. py file to get it to
运行那个主程序。 使用 py 文件
create our environment and install those
创建我们的环境并安装这些
dependencies. Uh, so if I were to pass
依赖项。 嗯，所以如果我把
this off to someone and they wanted to
这个交给别人，而他们想在
get their environment ready without
不
running the application, then they could
运行应用程序的情况下准备好环境，那么他们可以
simply use UV sync. And I'll show how
简单地使用 UV 同步。 接下来我会演示它是如何
this works. So first, let me delete that
运作的。 首先，让我再删除一下那个
virtual environment again. So it's not
虚拟环境。 所以它不在
within our project. And now if I pass
我们的项目范围内。 现在，如果我把
this off to someone and they have this
这个程序交给别人，而
on their machine, then they can simply
他们的电脑上也有这个程序，那么他们就可以直接
run UV sync. And when they run that, we
运行 UV 同步程序了。 运行该程序后，我们
can see that it recreated the exact same
可以看到它
environment using the UV lock file. And
使用 UV 锁定文件重新创建了完全相同的环境。
now if we wanted to remove a dependency,
现在，如果我们想移除一个依赖项，
then I could just say UV remove flask.
那么我就可以简单地说 UV remove flask。
And if I run that, it takes that off.
如果我运行那个程序，它就能把它移除。
And that would remove that package and
这样就会删除该软件包，并
update the PI project and lock file. And
更新 PI 项目和锁定文件。
then they could simply send that back to
然后他们就可以直接把文件发给
me without their virtual environment.
我，而无需使用他们的虚拟环境。
and I could run UV sync and get synced
我可以运行 UV 同步并
up with those dependencies. So, I find
与这些依赖项同步。 所以我觉得这一切都
all of this a lot easier, especially for
容易多了，特别是对于
beginners. Uh, instead of running five
初学者来说。 呃，我们不再需要运行五
to six different commands and having to
六个不同的命令，也不需要
understand virtual environments, uh,
了解虚拟环境，呃，
we've got a much more streamlined
我们现在有了一个更加精简的
process that does all the complexity be
流程，所有复杂的操作都在
behind the scenes. And one of the
后台完成。 随着时间的推移，
biggest advantages that you'll notice
你会发现 UV 的最大优势之一
with UV, especially over time, is its
是其
smart global caching system. Uh so this
智能的全局缓存系统。 嗯，这
means that if we have 10 different
意味着如果我们有 10 个不同的
projects that all use the same version
项目都使用相同版本
of Flask, uh UV only stores that Flask
的 Flask，那么 UV 只会将该 Flask
version and its dependencies once on our
版本及其依赖项存储在磁盘上一次
disk, which saves a lot of space. So
，从而节省大量空间。 所以
your environments still remain
你们的环境仍然
completely isolated from each other. So
彼此完全隔离。 所以
there's no risk of conflicts there. Uh
那里不存在冲突风险。
but you get the dispace savings and
但是，安装以前使用过的软件包可以节省空间并
major speed improvements when installing
大幅提高速度
packages that you've used before. And
。
that's especially noticeable when
当
recreating environments or setting up
重新创建环境或使用
new projects with familiar dependencies
熟悉的依赖项设置新项目时，这一点尤其明显，
because with pip and venv different
因为使用 pip 和 venv 时，
virtual environments for different
不同项目的不同虚拟环境
projects might contain duplicate copies
可能包含
of the same packages. Uh so not only do
相同软件包的重复副本。 这样不仅可以
you save disc space but you also save on
节省磁盘空间，还可以节省
download times and what used to take
下载时间，以前
minutes with pip can be almost
用画中画 (PIP) 需要几分钟才能完成的操作，
instantaneous with UV. And I know that
用 UV 几乎可以瞬间完成。 我知道
there's a lot of new tools out there and
现在有很多新工具，
it can get a bit overwhelming. So, some
这可能会让人有点不知所措。 所以，
of you may be thinking, "Okay, this
你们中的一些人可能会想，“好吧，这
looks cool, but I'm used to pip and I
看起来很酷，但我已经习惯了 pip，我
right now." Uh, well, the good thing
现在不想学习一个新工具。” 嗯，好处
about this is that UV provides a UV pip
在于 UV 提供了一个 UV pip 子
subcommand that acts as a direct faster
命令，可以直接
replacement for pip itself. So, you can
替代 pip，而且速度更快。 所以，如果您想逐步过渡，
actually just keep using familiar
实际上可以继续使用熟悉的
commands if you want to transition
命令
gradually. So, let me show you what I
。 那么，让我来解释一下我的
mean by that. Uh so let's say that we go
意思。 嗯，假设我们
back to our previous project where we
回到之前
used pip and install another package. So
使用 pip 安装另一个软件包的项目。 那么，
let me switch over to that old way
让我切换到
project that we created before. So in
我们之前创建的那个旧方法项目。 所以
here we haven't set this up with UV. If
这里我们还没有设置紫外线。 如果
I look at the files in this directory
我查看这个目录下的文件，
then we should only have our Python
应该只有我们的 Python
script and our
脚本和
requirements.txt file. So if I wanted to
requirements.txt 文件。 所以如果我
work on this, uh, we could activate the
想做这件事，我们可以激活
environment and then use pip to install
环境，然后使用 pip 安装
a package using pip. But UV has a pip
软件包。 但是 UV 有一个 pip
command that behaves the same as pip.
命令，其行为与 pip 相同。
And if you have a virtual environment in
如果你的项目中已经有虚拟环境
your project already, then it will find
，它会自动找到它
that for you. So if I wanted to add uh,
。 所以如果我想添加
numpy for example, then I could say uv
numpy，例如，那么我可以输入 uv，
and then pip install numpy. And if I run
然后输入 pip install numpy。 如果我运行该命令，
that then we can see that that
我们就可以看到它已经
installed. And now if I say uv pip list
安装成功了。 现在，如果我输入 uv pip list，
then we can see that now we have flask
我们可以看到现在有 flask
request and we also have numpy there. So
request，还有 numpy。 所以
this uh pip subcomand here is nice for
这个 pip 子命令对于
transitioning over to UV. Uh but you do
过渡到 UV 来说很不错。 但是这样你会
miss out on a lot of the functionality
错过
that makes UV so useful. So for example,
紫外线照射带来的很多实用功能。 例如，
uh since it's just doing what pip would
由于它只是执行 pip 会
do, it's not creating that pi project or
执行的操作，因此它不会在后台创建 pi 项目或
lock file in the background. So if I
锁定文件。 所以，如果我
look in this directory, then we can see
查看这个目录，就会发现里面
that we still only have the same files
仍然只有和以前一样的文件
as before. So if I wanted this
。 所以，如果我想让
requirements.txt file uh to be up to
requirements.txt 文件
date with the packages that we just
与我们刚刚安装的软件包保持最新状态
installed, then we'd have to do a uv pip
，那么我们就需要执行 uv pip
freeze uh to overwrite that. So, the
freeze 来覆盖它。 所以，
option to use pip commands is there if
如果你愿意，可以使用 pip 命令，
you want it, but I'd really recommend
但我强烈建议你直接
just getting started with using UV uh
使用 UV 及其
with its own commands. And I think
自身的命令。 我认为
you'll find it fairly easy to learn and
你会发现它很容易学习和
use. Now, if I wanted to migrate this
使用。 现在，如果我想把这个
project here over to using UV's workflow
项目迁移到使用 UV 的工作流程
instead of pips, then I could just say
而不是 pips，那么我只需输入
UVIT and run this. And that will create
UVIT 并运行它即可。 这将形成
the project structure that we saw
我们之前看到的项目结构
before. And then I'd have to add those
。 然后我需要
packages from the requirements.txt file.
从 requirements.txt 文件中添加这些软件包。
So first let me show that it created
首先，让我来展示一下它是如何创建
this project structure that we saw
我们之前看到的这个项目结构的
before. And now I want to add those
。 现在我想
packages from the requirements.txt file.
从 requirements.txt 文件中添加这些软件包。
To do that I can just say uv add- r
为此，我只需说 uv add- r
requirements.txt. And if I run that it
requirements.txt。 如果我运行那个命令，它
will install all of those. And if I look
会安装所有这些软件。 如果我
at the pi projectl file then we can see
查看 pi 项目文件，我们可以看到
that now all of those are listed in our
现在所有这些都已列在我们的
dependencies. So at that point if you
依赖项中。 所以，如果你当时
wanted to move forward only using uv
只想使用 uv，
then you could delete that
那么你可以删除
requirements.txt file and rely solely on
requirements.txt 文件，完全依赖
your pi project and lock files. Okay. So
你的 pi 项目和锁定文件。 好的。
now let me switch back over to uh the
现在让我切换回我
other directory that I created before in
之前在
this new app. Now, another really cool
这个新应用程序中创建的另一个目录。  UV 的另一个非常酷的
feature of UV is that it can replace pip
功能是它可以替代 pip
X for installing Pythonbased command
X 来安装基于 Python 的命令
line tools. Now, if you don't know what
行工具。 如果你不知道
Pip X does, it basically allows you to
Pip X 的作用，它基本上允许你
install Python command line tools that
安装 Python 命令行工具，
you can use anywhere on your system and
你可以在系统上的任何位置使用这些工具，而
not just in a specific project. Uh, so
不仅仅是在特定的项目中。 呃，就是那种
llinters, formatterers, things like
文本清理器、格式化器之类的东西
that. Uh those are things that you'll
。 嗯，这些东西你
likely just want to install once and use
可能只想安装一次，然后
across multiple different projects as
在多个不同的项目中使用，而
opposed to installing them in every
不是在每个
project individually. And we can also do
项目中单独安装。 我们也可以
this with UV. So for example, let's say
用紫外线做到这一点。 例如，假设
that we wanted to install Rough, which
我们想要安装 Rough，这
is a popular Python litter that's also
是一个流行的 Python 库，也是
made by Astral. So normally, uh you
由 Astral 开发的。 通常情况下，你
might install this with pip X, but we
可能会用 pip X 安装它，但我们也
can use UV instead. And this is a tool.
可以用 UV 来安装。 而这是一种工具。
So I can say UV tool install
所以可以说UV工具安装得很
rough. And what this does is it installs
粗糙。 这样做的好处是，它会
rough in an isolated environment but
在一个隔离的环境中进行粗略安装，但
makes it available on your path. So
使其在您的路径上可用。 那么
let's confirm that that's installed and
让我们确认一下它是否已安装并且
accessible from anywhere. Uh I'm on a
可以从任何地方访问。 呃，我用的是
Mac so I can do that by saying which
Mac，所以我可以通过说which
rough. And we can see that it did
rough来做到这一点。 我们可以看到它确实
install it here in my uh local bin
安装到了我的
directory of my home folder. So that
主文件夹的本地 bin 目录中。 所以它
should be available anywhere on the
应该可以在系统的任何位置访问
system. And rough is a llinter. So with
。 粗糙是一种疏通剂。
that installed, I can check my Python
安装完成后，我就可以检查我的Python
code. So if I wanted to check this
代码了。 所以如果我想检查这个
project, I could say rough check. It
项目，我可以说粗略检查一下。 它
says that all checks pass there. And if
说所有检查都在那里通过了。 如果
I had a more strict rough configuration,
我能有一个更严格的粗略配置，
then that might come back with some
那么或许可以进行一些
improvements uh to change my code in
改进，从而按照我想要的方式修改我的代码
ways that I want. And I'll be doing a
。 我近期也会做一个
rough tutorial in the near future also.
简易教程。   所以
Uh, so be sure that you're subscribed if
，如果您想在发布时收到通知，请确保您已订阅
released. Okay. So, it's just as easy to
。 好的。 所以，
remove a tool. So, let me clear my
拆卸工具也同样容易。 让我清空一下
terminal here. So, to remove a tool, I
终端。 所以，要移除一个工具，我
can say UV tool uninstall rough. And
可以说 UV 工具卸载很粗糙。
now, if I check my system again for that
现在，如果我再次检查我的系统以查找该
rough command, we can see that it's not
粗略命令，我们可以看到它没有被
found. Now, one really cool thing about
找到。  UV 的一个非常棒的优点
UV is that we don't even need to install
是，我们甚至不需要将
these tools permanently on our system.
这些工具永久安装到我们的系统中。
in order to use them. Uh so if you just
为了使用它们。 嗯，如果您只是
want to test out a tool or use it a few
想测试一下某个工具，或者想在
times for a specific task without
不永久安装的情况下，用它完成某个特定任务几次
permanently installing it, then we can
，那么我们可以
do that by saying UV tool run. So let me
通过说“UV 工具运行”来实现。 让我
clear this out. UV tool run. So if I
把话说清楚。  UV工具运行。 所以如果我
wanted to run that same rough check
想运行同样的粗略检查
command, then I could say rough check.
命令，那么我可以说粗略检查。
And we can see that that works just like
我们可以看到，它的效果和
it did before. But if I search for rough
以前一样好。 但是，如果我
on my system, then we can see that it's
在我的系统中搜索 rough，就会发现它并
not installed. So that UV tool run
没有安装。 因此，UV 工具运行
command installs it in a temporary
命令会将其安装在临时
environment, runs it, and then cleans it
环境中，运行它，然后在
up afterwards, which is super useful,
之后进行清理，这非常有用，
and it does it all very quickly. And
而且它完成所有这些操作的速度都非常快。
very popular in UV. Uh, so they've
在紫外线照射下，像这样运行不同的工具非常流行。 嗯，他们
actually made a shortcut for UV tool
实际上为 UV 工具运行创建了一个快捷方式
run, and that is UVX. So I can do the
，那就是 UVX。 所以，我
same thing just by saying uvx rough
只需说“uvx 粗略检查”就能做到同样的事情，
check and that is the same thing as this
这与这个
uv tool run rough check. So if I run
UV 工具运行粗略检查的效果是一样的。 所以如果我运行一下，
that we can see we get the same thing.
我们可以看到结果是一样的。
If I search for rough it's still not
如果我搜索“粗糙”，它仍然没有
installed. So that is super useful for
安装。 所以这对于
running tools without installing them.
无需安装即可运行工具来说非常有用。
Uh but I use rough a lot. So I'm
呃，但我经常用粗糙的。 所以我打算把它
that permanently. So I'll just go ahead
永久安装上。 那我就直接去做吧
and do that. and keep that installed.
。 并保持安装状态。
And we can check the tools that we have
我们可以
installed by saying UV tool list. And we
通过输入“UV工具列表”来查看我们已安装的工具。 我们
can see here that right now we only have
可以看到，目前我们只有粗略的粗略数据
rough. And we can upgrade those
。 如果您愿意，我们可以单独升级这些组件，
individually if you want, but most
但
likely uh you'd probably want to update
您可能更希望
them all at once. Uh to do this, I could
一次性全部升级。 嗯，要做到这一点，我可以
say UV tool upgrade and then we could
说UV工具升级，然后我们就可以在
just do a d-all here. If I run that, we
这里进行所有操作了。 如果我运行该命令，我们
can see that there's nothing to upgrade
可以看到
since we just installed that. So, I
由于我们刚刚安装了它，所以没有什么需要升级的。 所以，我
really like UV's tool integration here.
真的很喜欢UV在这里的工具集成。
Uh, it's taking all of these things that
嗯，它将以前
used to be separate tools like pip, pip
像 pip、pip
x, and virtual environments and making
x 和虚拟环境这样各自独立的工具整合起来，使
them feel naturally like they belonged
它们感觉就像一开始就属于同一个
as a single tool to begin with. And
工具一样自然。
there's even more that UV can do that we
紫外线还有更多我们
haven't covered. So, it has ways of
尚未提及的作用。 所以，它有
managing different Python versions, has
管理不同 Python 版本的方法，有
commands for building and uploading your
构建
own Python packages to Pippi, uh, and
自己的 Python 包并将其上传到 Pippi 的命令，
even has some features designed to help,
甚至还有一些旨在帮助
uh, build optimized Docker containers.
构建优化的 Docker 容器的功能。
But those are things that we could cover
但
in a more advanced tutorial if anyone is
如果有人感兴趣，我们可以在更高级的教程中讲解这些内容
interested in that. But I think what we
。 但我认为我们今天讨论的内容
went over here covers the majority of
涵盖了大多数人
what most of you will use UV for. Uh,
使用紫外线的大部分用途。 嗯，
I've been using it myself for some time
我自己已经用了一段时间了，
now and really don't see myself going
真的不觉得我会再像
environments the way that I was before.
以前那样使用画中画或虚拟环境了。
Uh, it's also uh what I'm going to be
嗯，这也是我
using in future videos. So, I wanted to
未来视频中会用到的东西。 所以，我想
make this quick tutorial that I could
制作这个简短的教程，以便
point people towards if they see me
将来如果有人
using UV in a future video and have
在视频中看到我使用 UV 模式，并
questions about that or why I'm using
对此或我为什么使用 UV 模式而不是
that over PIP. But with that said, I
画中画模式有疑问，我可以把他们引到这个教程中。 不过，我
think that's going to do it for this
想这期
video. Hopefully now you feel like you
视频就到此为止了。 希望现在您对
have a good idea of how UV works and how
UV 的工作原理以及
it can simplify your Python package
它如何简化您的 Python 包
management. Uh we've seen how it
管理有了很好的了解。 我们已经看到它如何用
replaces multiple tools with a single
一个界面取代多个工具，
interface and how it can be dramatically
以及它如何比
faster than those traditional tools. Now
那些传统工具快得多。 接下来，
in a future video I'm going to be
我将在一段视频中
covering Rough which is a llinter built
介绍 Rough，它是同一团队开发的一款排序工具，
by the same team and that's another tool
也是
that I've migrated over to using in my
我在
daily workflow. So, big props to the
日常工作流程中迁移使用的另一款工具。 所以，要好好夸夸
team at Astral because they've
Astral 团队，因为他们
lately uh that have become super popular
最近确实推出了一些很棒的工具，这些工具
in the Python community. But if anyone
在 Python 社区中非常受欢迎。 但如果大家对
in this video, then feel free to ask in
本视频内容有任何疑问，欢迎在
the comment section below and I'll do my
下方评论区留言，我会
best to answer those. And if you enjoy
尽力解答。 如果您喜欢
these tutorials and would like to
这些教程并想
support them, then there are several
支持它们，
ways you can do that. The easiest way is
您可以通过以下几种方式进行支持。 最简单的方法就是点
to simply like the video and give it a
赞视频并竖起
thumbs up. Also, it's a huge help to
大拇指。 此外，将
share these videos with anyone who you
这些视频分享给任何你
think would find them useful. And if you
认为会觉得有用的人，也会非常有帮助。 如果你
have the means, you can contribute
有能力，可以
through Patreon or YouTube. And there
通过 Patreon 或 YouTube 进行捐助。
description section below. Be sure to
下面描述部分提供了这些页面的链接。 记得
subscribe for future videos. And thank
订阅，以便观看更多视频。
you all for watching.
感谢大家的观看。